So from that glass of orange juice you
might be sipping on this morning to the
fruit in your fridge, even the prices at
the grocery store, much of it as you
probably know starts in Florida. But
right now nearly the entire state is
drying out and a harsh winter has only
made things worse putting those farmers
under intense pressure threatening crops
that feed and fuel the rest of our
country. NewsNation's Brooke Shafer is
live for us in Miami. Brooke, they're
calling this one of the toughest
stretches in decades. Just how serious
is this drought right now?
>> Extremely serious, Marci. In fact, in
parts of the state in DeSoto County just
further north of where we are, that
county is now in extreme drought. It's
actually the first time that that has
happened since 2001 according to state
records and they are not alone here. In
fact, about 95% of Florida according to
officials is now in moderate drought or
worse with conditions arriving a lot
earlier, months earlier in fact, than
normal. State agriculture officials
estimate recent freezes and dry
conditions have caused more than a
billion dollars in crop damage across
Florida. And Marci, that is prompting
the state to move quickly as farmers of
course try and deal with this and the
state tries to protect what is a
billion-dollar industry across Florida.
>> Thank you for watching. Subscribe below
and download our NewsNation app right
now on your phone and you will get
fact-based unbiased news for all
Americans.